## **Mohamed Hassan Mahmoud El-Gendy**

Address: 12/14 Aziz be allah St. El Zayton, Cairo, EGYPT Phone: + (202) 26525447,

**Mobile:** + (2) 01003370105

E-mail: eng.mhassan88@gmail.com

# **Career Objectives:-**

I am an electrical engineer and due to my current job in the oil and gas filed as an ROV Pilot/ Engineer I got a very good experience with the mechanical and hydraulic, as when you check the responsibilities you will find out that I have to be responsible of everything related with the ROV starting from maintenance till operation. As an engineer, I am seeking for a full-time job that fulfills my passion in creativity, innovation and challenge. Hence, I hope to find this job in your reputable organization to settle a stable, promising and rewarding career.

## **Educational data:-**

### **➤** University:-

BSc. Of Engineering, Faculty of engineering,

Ain Shams University 2009

Major: Electrical power and machines department.

Grade: Very good.

Graduation project grade is Excellent

◆ Graduation project is "Airfield Lighting System Design of Sharm El Sheikh Airport.

# > Secondary school:-

Amoun private School

## Work experience:-

- o Jan 2014-Till now ROV Pilot at Deeptech oil services.
- April 2013-Dec 2013 Cased hole logging and perforation engineer at SAPESCO (Sahara Petroleum services)
- Feb 2012-April 2013 offshore and onshore Memory Gauges engineer at measurement services department at SAPESCO (Sahara Petroleum services)

- May 2010-jan 2012 Maintenance engineer in offshore rigs and onshore rigs in EDC (Egyptian Drilling Company) and Also Saudi Arabia branch-DPS (Drilling petroleum services) with ARAMCO.
- o Sept.2009-Mar.2010 Maintenance engineer Working in ideal standard for tunnel and shuttle kiln.

## **Training courses & certifications:**

- > BOSIET "Basic Offshore Safety Induction and Emergency Training" Valid Till 2018
- > OGUK "Oil and Gas UK" medical certificate for working offshore Valid Till 2019
- ➤ <u>Introduction to cased hole logging and perforation and explosive safety at SAPESCO training center</u>
- > Training in ISAP Oil & Gas industry safety and health standards in accordance with OSHA standards
- > Arab academy for Science, Technology & Maritime Transport:
  - o T-Bossiest, advanced fire fighting and first aid
- in Randy Smith training center:
  - ♦ Safety management system.
  - ♦ Lifting, manual handling.
  - ♦ Lockout/tag out, respiratory protection, spill protection.
  - ♦ H2S protection.
  - ♦ SCR.
  - ♦ AC Generator.
  - ♦ Stop employee.

# **Summer training:-**

- o 05/08/2007-16/08/2007 in Egyptian Radio and Television Union (Maspero)
- $\circ$   $1 \vee / \cdot \wedge / \cdot \cdot \wedge \cdot 1 / \cdot \wedge / \cdot \cdot \wedge$  in Egemac.
- o 01/07/2008-31/07/2008 in ABB Arab.
- o 01/04/2010-01/05/2010 in Deutschland as firefighting systems designer

# Additional activities:-

 Successfully Completed the Entrepreneurial Master Workshop KEY CDC in Association with INJAZ

# **Summary of Qualifications**

#### **Technical Skills**

As per my studies as electrical power Engineer I got technical skills of troubleshooting electronics, electrical equipment and any mean of power inputs, control and circuits wiring between devices.

I gained some experience from my work as an ROV Pilot to understand and troubleshoot the hydraulics and mechanical circuits as well as the fiber optics communication. With accumulative flying hours (665.5 hours)

#### **Tools**

- Schilling T4 7 function manipulator
- o Rig Master 5 function manipulator
- o TA 60 5 function manipulator
- Profilers
- Pipe trackers
- o Torque tools
- o Gasket replacement tools
- o Regan latch tool
- Hot stabs
- o CP probe contact and proximity
- o UT probe contact
- o Zip pump
- Subsea Grinders
- Subsea Cutter
- Octane Gyro
- o DVL (Doppler velocity log)

# **Equipment Experience**

- o Perry Triton XLS 43
- o Perry Triton XLS 57
- o SMD Quantum 9
- o SMD Quasar 24
- o SMD Quasar 25

## **Interpersonal skills:-**

- Ability to work well under pressure.
- Ability to learn new tasks quickly.
- Can work individually and as an effective team member.
- Good at meeting deadlines.

## **Language skills:-**

- Good command of spoken, reading and written English.
- My mother tongue is Arabic.

### **Computer skills:-**

- O Proficient user for Microsoft Office, windows and internet.
- Very Good knowledge of using AutoCAD, Octave3.2.4,
   C Programming Language and MATLAB program.

# **Personal information:-**

Date of birth: 5<sup>th</sup> January, 1988

Marital status: Married
Nationality: Egyptian
Military status: Exempted
Driving license: Valid

Seaman passport: Valid

References furnished upon request